This is a work of fiction.
Any resemblance to real persons, groups or events is purely coincidental.
Wow, they got that out fast. They're really into this.
こんな早朝から張ってるなんて
気合いが入ってるじゃないか
ま 気合いなら僕も負けないけど
But not as much as me!
Global Action Club
よー 福部
Hey, Fukube. You're late.
遅かったな
や おはよう
Hey! Morning.
参ったな
This is bad. I can't let Juumoji get away with them around.
これじゃ十文字を泳がせるのは難しいか
しかし 朝から張り込みとは精が出るね
You're all here pretty early. You seem pretty fired up.
お前もな
You too.
ここに探偵志願者たちが待機してるってことは
If these would-be detectives are still standing around here,
犯行はまだみたいだね
that means the theft hasn't been committed yet.
All right, Juumoji, if you're gonna strike then now's the time!
さあ 十文字 来るなら来い
@ 湮·Molly／小然·酸菜／喵儿·小冷／时末·竭力而为
KamiGami
Today is a real mess, but I get over it with a sigh
複雑に構えた今日が 息を呑んで澄ましてる
身に覚えあるだろう 君はどうしたい
You get the idea, right?
What do you wanna do?
何もなかったそぶりで  かばう痛みはもう
You act as if nothing happened
As if your heart didn't ache
心強いくらいに 急かすんだ
It almost feels encouraging,
the way you're rushing me
掴んでこぼして 不完全な僕たちが
Hold it and let it overflow
We're all imperfect
光って見えない 未来の自分を創れるなら
I can't see it well in the light,
but if we can change our future selves
目覚めるまま走れ 蜃気楼を追い越して
Wake up and run
Go and surpass the mirage
変わりたいまま走れ 自由な違和感で
Try to change and run
with the discomfort of freedom
届きそうな輝きと今を選んでいこう
We can reach that shining light
Follow it into the present
飛びたつ手を知らない
Don't hesitate to act
深い 浅い 呼吸を重ねて
Deep or quick, just keep breathing
Hyouka
最后的目标
The Final Target
It's the last day! The most crucial moment!
いよいよ最終日です
正念場です
I see.
なるほどね
I feel like I've met her somewhere before...
今の方 どこかでお会いしたような
Using the Juumoji incident to help sell Hyouka wasn't a bad idea.
十文字事件を餌にして氷菓を売ろうという発想は悪くない
But that won't be enough to sell them all.
だが それでも完売にはすこし足りないか
Should I consider the alternatives?
考えてみるか
Dunno if it'll all work out though.
うまく行くかは分からないが
Nothing's happening.
何も起きんなあ
That's true.
確かにね
Juumoji's next target is the Quiz Society...
十文字の狙いはクイズ研
But no... What would he steal from them now that the main event's over?
いやいや まさか
イベントが終わったクイズ研から何を盗むんだ
I'm starving. Let's go.
俺飽きたし 行くわ
Yeah, I've had enough too.
何か 俺ももういいや
What's wrong, Juumoji? Is the mysterious thief afraid of a crowd?
どうした 怪盗十文字
人の多さに恐れを成したのか
What?!
何だと
Did something happen?
何かあったの
That bastard Juumoji faked us out.
十文字め フェイント掛けやがった
Faked us out?
フェイント
Was it the Quiz Society?
まさかクイズ研
No, the Light Music Club.
いいや 軽音部だ
They had some strings stolen.
弦がやられた
The Light Music Club? But...
軽音部 軽音部だって
Are you sure about that?!
それ 本当なんだろうね
If you don't believe me, check for yourself!
そう思うなら自分で確かめばいいだろが
Later!
じゃあな
Wait!
待って
It's pointless.
無駄か
Seems like the Light Music Club got hit.
何か 軽音部がやられたらしいぞ
Is that true?
それ本当か
Juumoji is far more flexible than I could have anticipated.
十文字の柔軟性は僕の予想と能力を大きく上回ってる
Conventional methods won't cut it this time.
正攻法では通じない
I must rethink my strategy.
考え直さなきゃ
How else can I catch him, if not red-handed?
現行犯逮捕以外に 僕に何ができる
Target: Sell all 2OO copies!
82 sold
When it sells, it sells well!
売れる時は売れるもんだな
The twenty copies that Chitanda gave to Irisu sold out,
委託した20部も売り切れて
so today she took another ten.
千反田が追加で10部持っていったし
And we've sold another nine in total since this morning.
朝から通算9部
I have high hopes for the rest of the day.
これは今後に期待が持てる
It's Saturday all right.
さすが土曜日
おっーす
Hey!
Saving energy as usual, I see.
相変わらず省エネに勤しんでるわね
Sis! You really came!
姉貴 本当に来るとは
You should be grateful your big sister came all the way to check up on you!
可愛い弟のために様子を見に来たお姉様に感謝しなさいよ
Here.
はい
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございます
What's that? It's not your style.
何それ
あんたに似合わないわね
これは わらしべプロトコルだ
I'm carrying out my own One Red Paperclip trade.
That pen turned into this mirror.
万年筆が手鏡になった
You bartered your way up?
要するに 物々交換ってこと
Yeah, pretty much.
まあな
Okay, then...
へえ じゃ
I'll take this.
これ もらうわね
In exchange... here.
代わりに
はい
What?
何だ
Dead at Dusk?
「夕べには骸に」
A manga?
漫画か
You might be able to kill some time with this, but it all depends on you.
これが暇つぶしになるかどうかはあんた次第ね
What do you mean?
どういう意味だ
Later!
じゃ行くわ
Hey!
お おい
Anshin'in Takuha?
安心院鐸玻
"How did you like Dead at Dusk?
「夕べには骸に」 いかがでしたか
It feels weird to say this myself, but I think it turned out pretty well.
自分で言うのも何なんですが
結構いい出来栄えだと思います
Well, I only helped with the backgrounds and hardly did anything else.
まあ 私は背景を手伝ったぐらいで
ほとんど何もしてないんですが
If you enjoyed it, that's thanks to the author and illustrator."
この漫画を楽しんでもらえたなら
私じゃなく 原作と作画の手柄です
So Anshin'in Takuha was a team name?
「安心院鐸玻」ってのは チーム名みたいなもんか
"Not all of us are members of the Manga Lab.
私たちは全員漫画研究会に属しているわけではありません
ただ漫画が好きで 話しているうちに気が合って
We simply share a fondness for manga, and as we talked, our ideas fit together.
We decided to write our own manga, and this is the result.
それじゃ書いてみようかってことで書かれたのがこの話です
I think it's not half bad for a first try, but we shouldn't praise ourselves too much.
処女作としてはかなりのものだと思いますが
あんまり身内褒めになってもよくありません
We'll let you, the readers, be the judge.
これを手に取ってくれた人の評価に任せるとしましょう
さて 私たちは今回一回で解散するつもりはありません
We don't want to split up after just one project, either.
We've already started on our next project for next year's Kan'ya Fair.
来年のカンヤ祭目指し もうスタートしています
We decided to change the genre completely and do a mystery story.
原作のAは 次回は作風をコロンと変えて
ミステリー風に攻めると言っています
We're thinking of giving a famous Christie novel a few twists.
何でも
クリスティーの超有名作を一ひねり二ひねりできないか企んでいるとか
We've already decided on the title, so without further ado:
タイトルはもうできているそうです
予告します
The title of our next project will be "Kudryavka's Order".
次回作のタイトルは「クドリャフカの順番」
Yes, another grim-sounding one.
また暗い題名を
Let us meet again at next year's Kan'ya Fair.
ではまた来年 カンヤ祭の次期にお会いしましょう
Anshin'in Takuha."
「安心院鐸玻」
Kudryavka's Order?
「クドリャフカの順番」
I don't know who or what Kudryavka is, but the word "order" is interesting.
クドリャフカが何かは知らないが
順番という単語が引っ掛かる
And "a famous Christie novel"?
それに クリスティーの超有名作
You might be able to kill some time with this, but it all depends on you.
これが暇つぶしになるかどうかはあんた次第ね
Sis, I sure hope you didn't bring something that's gonna cause even more trouble for me.
姉貴め まさか厄介ごとを持ち込んできたんじゃないだろな
Radio Room
Excuse me!
すみません
あの 放送部部長の吉野さんですよね
You're Yoshino, the president of the Radio Club, right?
そうだけど 君は
I am, but who are you?
Nice to meet you. I'm the Classics Club's president, Chitanda Eru.
こんにちは
古典部の部長をしています 千反田えるです
I'd like to—
吉野さん
君が古典部の部長さん
You're the president of the Classics Club?!
This is perfect! I was just going to look for you!
ちょうどよかった 君に会いに行くところだったんだ
Would you like to join us as our guest for our lunchtime show?
君 お昼のラジオのゲストに出てみない
I think it'd be awesome to promote you as the president of Juumoji's final target.
十文字最後の標的の部長って触れ込みが一番受けると思うんだ
What do you say?
どう
I didn't even have to ask!
願ってもないチャンスです
I'd be very happy to!
こちらこそ よろしくお願いします
Then I'll see you at twelve in the radio room!
じゃ 12時に放送室ね
The show starts at twelve-thirty! Thanks in advance!
放送は12時半だから よろしくー
Okay!
はい
I'm back!
戻りました
Hey, Chitanda!
や 千反田さん
How are we doing? Has anything happened?
お疲れ様です
何か進展ありました
They skipped "ku" and stole some strings from the Light Music Club.
「く」が抜かされて 軽音部から弦が盗まれたんだ
We'll need to rethink our approach from the beginning.
一から考え直しだよ
What do you think, Oreki?
どう思います 折木さん
He's totally engrossed in some indie manga. He's been like that for a while.
同人漫画に夢中でさっきからずっとこの調子なんだ
That was good.
いいぞ これ
Really?
へええ
Huh?
あら
What?
どうしたの
この絵 どこかで見たような気が
I think I've seen this picture somewhere.
Must be your imagination. My sister just gave me this.
錯覚だろ 姉貴が持ってきたやつだぞ
いいえ 間違いありません
No, I'm certain.
Chitanda, we don't have time.
千反田 今はそれ所じゃないだろ
I...
私
I can't stop thinking about it!
私 気になります
Here we go.
出た
It's too much to bear!
ここまで来てるんです
Hold it back!
呑み込め
I can't!
無理です
Do something about it!
そこをなんとか
Show me another page too!
別のページも見せてください
Here.
ほら
Thanks!
ありがとうございます
This picture!
この絵 会議室前に張られていたポスターの絵と似ています
This looks like the poster in front of the meeting room!
Are
you
telling
me
to forget
everything
that
happened?
うん 確かに
You're right.
Oreki, please let me borrow this manga for a bit!
折木さん この漫画少し貸してください
I want to compare them!
見比べたいんです
Okay, but bring it back soon! I need it.
分かった ただすぐに返してくれ
ちょっと要るんだ
はい
Okay!
やっぱりこっちの絵だよな
It's this picture, right?
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much!
I'm done!
上がりです
What next?
次は
お姉さん 写真いいかな
Whatever you'd like.
適当に書いて
駄目です
はい
I'll go and change the water.
水そろそろ替えてきますね
Ah, thanks.
うん ありがとう
Photos won't do!
写真は駄目です
Whoops!
おっと
ご ごめん 伊原
I-I'm sorry, Ibara!
I really didn't...
私 そんなつもりじゃ
It's okay... It was khaki in the first place,
大丈夫 元がカーキ色だからね
so it won't be too apparent... I hope...
目立たないよ たぶん
Ibara?
伊原
Excuse me, president. Please take care of the rest.
すみません 部長
後 よろしくお願いします
You should take off the Rainbow Parakeet costume.
七色インコの服 着替えないと
Please don't worry about it.
気にしないでください
Mayaka!
摩耶花さん
Chi?
チ―ちゃん
Do you have a minute?
今ちょっといいですか
あれ ジャージ
Sweats?
Yeah, I changed.
うん 着替えたんだ
So what did you want?
それでどうしたの
This!
これなんです
何でチーちゃんがこれ持ってるの？
How did you get this?!
It's not mine, it's Oreki's.
私のではなく 折木さんのなんです
Why would Oreki...
何で折木が
お姉さんが持ってきたそうですよ
He said his sister gave it to him.
Do you know this manga, Mayaka?
摩耶花さん この漫画のこと知ってるんですか
Yeah, kinda...
まあ 知ってるよ
You know the culture fair poster, right?
あのですね
文化祭の宣伝ポスターはあるんですが
I can't stop thinking about how the same person must have drawn both that poster and this manga!
そのポスターを描いた人とこの漫画を描いた人が同じ人なのか
私 気になるんです
Where's this poster?!
そのポスター どこ？
In front of the meeting room!
会議室の脇です
よし 行こう
Let's go!
秋分
阴阳相半也
Autumn Equinox
When light and dark are in balance.
Hyouka
What do you think?
どうですか
I'm 99% sure it's the same person.
99%同じ人ね
The way the ears are drawn match perfectly.
耳の処理の仕方がまったく同じ
I see! Thank you very much!
そうですか
ありがとうございます
I feel like a great weight's been lifted off my chest!
胸の痞えがおりました
It's interesting, isn't it?
気になるよね
Yeah.
はい
Why don't we find out who drew it?
ねえ 誰が描いたか 聞いてみない？
Good idea! I can't stop thinking about it!
そうですね 気になります
Coming!
はい
Good afternoon, Tanabe.
こんにちは 田名辺さん
Hey, you're...
やあ 君は… えっと…
From the Classics Club.
古典部です
What is it this time?
そうそう で また何か？
Sorry for the trouble, but do you know who drew that poster over there?
ちょっとすみません そこに張ってあるポスター
誰が描いたのか分かりますか
Ah, that was Kugayama.
ああ それなら 陸山だよ
You mean Kugayama Muneyoshi, the student council president?
陸山宗芳さんですか 生徒会長の？
Yeah. We pestered him to draw something.
ああ 「お前も何か描け」ってせっついたんだ
Not half bad, is it?
けっこういい出来だろ
Yes, I think it's wonderful!
はい とても素晴らしい出来だと思います
He'll be happy to hear that.
本人が聞いたら喜ぶよ
Now I know both the author and the illustrator!
原作に続いて作画まで分かるなんて
Should I ask him about it?
本人に聞いてみようかな
Maybe the dream team will reunite!
もうしかしたら 黄金コンビは続いてるかも
Earth Sci. Prep. room
We found out!
分かりました
Was it really the same?
やっぱり同じだった？
て あれ 摩耶花ジャージ？
Mayaka, what are you doing in a sweatsuit? What happened to the Manga Lab?
漫研は？
I got away from my shift.
うん 換わってもらった
It really was the same person! We found out his name too!
同じ方でした 名前も分かりました
おお よかったな
That's wonderful!
It's Kugayama Muneyoshi! It was a real surprise!
陸山宗芳さんでした 驚きです
うん 有名人か
Is he someone famous?
ほ 奉太郎 冗談で言ってるんだよね
Houtarou, are you kidding?
Do you know him?
知ってるのか
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Kugayama
Muneyoshi
(student
council
president,
executive
producer
of the
Kan'ya Fair)
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Kugayama
Muneyoshi
(student
council
president,
executive
producer
of the
Kan'ya Fair)
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Kugayama
Muneyoshi
(student
council
president,
executive
producer
of the
Kan'ya Fair)
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Kugayama
Muneyoshi
(student
council
president,
executive
producer
of the
Kan'ya Fair)
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Kugayama
Muneyoshi
(student
council
president,
executive
producer
of the
Kan'ya Fair)
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Kugayama
Muneyoshi
(student
council
president,
executive
producer
of the
Kan'ya Fair)
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Kugayama
Muneyoshi
(student
council
president,
executive
producer
of the
Kan'ya Fair)
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Kugayama
Muneyoshi
(student
council
president,
executive
producer
of the
Kan'ya Fair)
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Kugayama
Muneyoshi
(student
council
president,
executive
producer
of the
Kan'ya Fair)
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Kugayama
Muneyoshi
(student
council
president,
executive
producer
of the
Kan'ya Fair)
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Kugayama
Muneyoshi
(student
council
president,
executive
producer
of the
Kan'ya Fair)
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Kugayama
Muneyoshi
(student
council
president,
executive
producer
of the
Kan'ya Fair)
Organizers
Yasaki Keita (student
council vice-president)
Kugayama
Muneyoshi
(student
council
president,
executive
producer
of the
Kan'ya Fair)
The council president.
生徒会長
Oh, I see!
ああ なるほどな
I thought he was Rikuyama all along.
ずっと「りくやま」だと思ってた
So that means that Kugayama was the illustrator for Anshin'in Takuha?
ということは この「安心院鐸玻」のうち
絵を描いたのはその陸山ってことか
"Anshin'in"? What are you talking about?
「あんしんいん」ってなんだよ
You read that as "Ajimu". It's a place in Kyuushuu.
それは「あじむ」と読むんだよ
九州の地名さ
Is that really something I can't live without knowing?
それは人生において必須知識なのか
あのう 読み方でしたら ここに小さくローマ字で書いてありますよ
By the way, the reading is written here in small Latin letters.
Oh.
Kugayama did the illustrations, but the story is by Anjou Haruna.
それ 絵は陸山先輩だけど
原作は安城春菜って人だって
You know about this?
ほー お前 これのこと知ってたのか
I love that manga!
大好きな漫画よ 去年この文化祭で買ったの
I bought it at last's year's culture fair!
Wow, Ibara just straight out said she loved it...
あの伊原がはっきり大好きと言うとは
Oreki, can I have that?
ねえ 折木
それ ちょっと貸してくれない？
Sure you can, but wait a little.
構わないが 少し待ってくれ
I'm still using it.
まだ使うんだ
You're using it?
使う？
Oh right! I managed to get some airtime on the Radio Club's lunchtime program!
そうです 実は 私放送部のお昼のラジオに出ることになったんです
What?
なんと！
That's amazing, Chi!
チーちゃん すごいじゃない
Not bad! That's wonderful news!
やるね 出演までこぎ着けるとは
Now selling all the copies of  Hyouka might be more than just a dream!
これで氷菓の完売も見えてきたね
I'll teach you the basics of how to speak on air.
じゃあ 僕がゲストの極意を伝授してあげるよ
Really?
本当ですか
Firstly, your time is limited to about five minutes.
まず第一に ゲストの時間ってのは五分くらいしかないんだ
So it all depends on how much you can impress people in that short time.
だから その短時間でどれだけ目立てるかだよ
Ah, I see.
The Kan'ya Fair Guide...
カンヤ祭の歩き方 園芸部 お料理研
なるほど
Secondly, you must make the Classics Club famous!
で 第二 古典部を援護する
The Gardening Club... The Cooking Club... The Light Music Club...
Okay! Leave it to me!
はい 任せてください
軽音部 クリスティの超有名作 クドリャフカの順番
A very famous Christie novel... Kudryavka's Order...
I'll be counting on you!
頼んだよ
What?
何だ？
How is it?
どうです？
What?
何が
Nothing...
いえ
Whatever.
ま いいか どうせ考えに煮詰まっていたところだ
I'm close to a conclusion.
I'll need to talk to them about it, but...
本来なら こいつらに相談しながら考えを進めたいが
Chitanda is in the way.
千反田が邪魔だなあ
If she found out what I'm about to do, she'd be against it.
俺がやろうとしていることを知ったら 反対するに違いない
里志 すまんが ちょっと来てくれ
Satoshi, could you come with me for a moment?
So you really did figure something out, Houtarou?
やっぱり何か分かったね 奉太郎
Really, Oreki?
本当ですか 折木さん
Know when to keep your mouth shut, goddamn it!
要らん勘を働かせるな！
You see that light in Chitanda's eyes?!
千反田の目の色が変ってしまったじゃないか！
Did you notice something?
何か気付いたんですか
No! Nothing at all!
気付いてない 気付いてない
Then it's not about the Juumoji incident?
じゃあ 十文字事件のことじゃないんですか
Well...
いや うん…
Hey, Oreki...
ちょっと 折木
I've... I've been thinking about it all this time, so why did you only ask Fukube...
私だって
私だって とっても気になってるのに
どうして福部さんだけ
I shouldn't take this any further.
参ったな かくなるうえは
Yes, it's about the Juumoji incident.
確かに十文字事件のことだ
Then please let us know too—
じゃあ 私たちもぜひ
However, it's quite a dirty story. You okay with that?
ものすごく卑猥な話だが いいか
So what's this "dirty story" of yours?
で 聞かせておくれよ 卑猥な話をさ
Sorry for dragging you out here.
無理に連れ出して 悪かったな
Oh, I don't mind.
なあに 構わないさ
It's not like I have some grand idea.
別にたいした考えがあるわけじゃない
There's just a few things that don't fit the big picture.
ただ ちょっと腑に落ちん点が幾つも出てきてなあ
I think that means something.
それが意味を持っているような気がするんだ
Was there some hidden connection between the clubs that got hit?
被害にあった部活に隠された繋がりでもあったのかい
No, that's not it either.
いや 別にそうじゃないな
Then what? Did the mysterious thief Juumoji make some fatal mistake?
なら 怪盗十文字の些細なミスでも見つけ出したとか
That isn't it either.
それもちと違うかな
What?
何だよ
It's neither?
どっちでもない？
There are over a thousand suspects.
容疑者は千人以上だよ
Were you planning to find the culprit without a connection or a mistake on their part?
それなのに 繋がりもミスも見つけず 犯人を特定しようっていうのかい
Kinda.
まあ そうだな
How?!
どうやってさ！
I don't know about the culprit yet. I just want to sum up my thoughts.
まあ 犯人がどうとかいうわけじゃない
少し考えをまとめたいんだ
Let's hear it. I expect great things of you, Houtarou.
聞かせてよ
期待してるよ 奉太郎
First: Why would Juumoji steal ten items from ten clubs?
第一に なぜ十文字は十の部活から十の品を盗むのか
That's just what we theorised he'd do, based on his name.
これは署名から読み取って 仮定しただけだがな
And that theory isn't holding steady either.
その仮定も 今や疑わしいけどね
Second: Why did they leave greeting cards behind at the scene of the crime?
第二に なぜ現場にグリーティングカードを残すのか
This, huh?
これだね
Third: Why do they use the word "lost"? It'd be more natural to say that they'd "taken" it.
第三に なぜ「失われた」という言葉を使うのか
lost
「いただいた」とかが普通じゃないか
Fourth: Why do they leave the Kan'ya Fair guide behind?
第四に なぜカンヤ祭の歩き方を残すのか
That's not the only thing with a list of clubs in it.
部活の一覧が載ってるのはあれだけじゃない
So why are they sticking just to that?
なぜあれに拘る
I've got one too, by the way.
ちなみに それもあるよ お料理研のやつ
I picked it up after the cooking competition.
Fifth: Why the Gardening Club and the Cooking Club?
第五に なぜ園芸部とお料理研なのか
There are other clubs that start with the same sound in Japanese.
「え」や「お」がつく部活はほかにもある 特にお料理研
Especially the Cooking Club.
It's not even common to write it in that way.
普通なら料理研だと思うぞ
And that leads us to whether the Classics Club or the Artisan Club will be targeted.
それは古典部と工作部 どっちが狙われるかって問題にも直結するね
Sixth, and this is the weirdest: Why did they skip "ku" and go straight for "ke"?
第六に こいつが一番おかしい
なぜ「く」を飛ばして 「け」を盗んだのか
That's was to elude watchful eyes.
それは警戒を掻い潜るためだよ
グローバルアクトクラブは物を盗めるような状況じゃなかった
You couldn't steal a speck of dust from the Global Action Club without someone noticing.
Seventh: this.
第七に これだ
That manga has nothing to do with this.
この漫画は別に関係ないでしょ
That might not be true.
それがそうでもないかもしれん
Satoshi, what are Christie's most famous works?
里志 クリスティの超有名作といえば？
Let's see... And Then There Were None, Murder on the Orient Express,
そうだね
「そして誰もいなくなった」
The Murder of Roger Ackroyd, and The ABC Murders.
「オリエント急行の殺人」
「アクロイド殺し」
「ABC殺人事件」
Those four, I guess.
その四つかな
If they came up with a retelling of one of those stories called Kudryavka's Order,
ひねって漫画にして
「クドリャフカの順番」というタイトルをつけるとするなら
it'd most likely be based off the ABC Murders.
俺は「ABC殺人事件」だと思っている
Kudryavka was a dog that was sent into space in a test launch and never returned alive.
クドリャフカって
昔実験でロケットに乗せられて 帰ってこられなかった犬のことだね
Wouldn't that imply And Then There Were None?
僕なら非業の死というイメージで 「そして誰も」かな
This is still just a theory, so it's okay if we don't agree.
まあ これは想像の範疇だから 一致しなくてもいいさ
I think I understand what you're trying to say.
なんだか奉太郎が言いたいことが分かった気がするよ
Satoshi, are they selling a manga titled Kudryavka's Order at this fair?
里志 この文化祭で「クドリャフカの順番」って漫画は売られているのか
Nope, I heard nothing like that at from General Affairs.
いや 総務員にそんな話は来てない
And if the Manga Lab had something to do with it, Mayaka would've mentioned it.
もし漫研で出てたなら 摩耶花が何か言ってるだろうし
Then...
ならばだ
They published Dead at Dusk at last year's fair.
去年の文化祭で「夕べには骸に」という漫画が出た
In the afterword, it said they'd publish a manga this year based on a famous Christie novel with "a few twists".
その後書きで
「来年はクリスティの超有名作をひねった漫画を出す」と予告してあった
That novel is probably either And Then There Were None or The ABC Murders.
その作品は推測で 「そして誰もいなくなった」か「ABC殺人事件」だ
And then this year, there's a series of incidents clearly inspired by The ABC Murders.
そして 予告された今年
明らかに「ABC殺人事件」からいただいたような事件が起きている
Is that a coincidence?
こいつは偶然か？
So you say that the Juumoji incident was originally announced in Dead at Dusk?
つまり 奉太郎は十文字事件は「夕べには骸に」で予告されていた
と言いたいんだね
I can't imagine they're not connected at all.
まあ まったく関係がないとは思えないくらいかな
I even feel like Juumoji is trying not to cause too much trouble or
十文字にはできるだけ迷惑をかけず
かつ邪魔されずに十文字事件を完遂させた意志すら感じる
disrupt the fair's events too much during their chain of thefts.
It doesn't feel like they're just doing it for the thrill of it.
愉快犯とは思えない
But then why did they skip "ku"?
なのに「く」を飛ばしたのはなぜだ
They had plenty of ways to pull it off.
やりようはいくらでもあっただろうに
Satoshi, this incident has some meaning to it.
里志 この事件 何か意味があるぞ
I'm going back.
僕は戻るよ
I'm a bit worried about Chitanda too.
千反田さんも心配だしね
You're right. I'll leave that to you.
そうだな 頼む
I'll have a look through the stuff you gave me.
俺はお前から借りたものを少し見てみるよ
Satoshi!
里志 千反田に「こ」のつくものを用意するように伝えてくれ
Tell Chitanda to get something ready that starts with "ko".
Bait for the culprit, right? I thought about that one already.
犯人を釣る餌だね 考えてるさ
I'll get some copy papers.
校了原稿を用意しておくよ
I'm counting on you, Houtarou.
期待してるよ 奉太郎
On air
We'll be going on air at the cue.
キューに合わせて入るからね
はい
Five seconds. Four.
五秒前  四 三
You're listening to Yoshino Yasukuni's Radio Beat special!
吉野康邦のRADIO BEAT特別版
Good morning to you all!
はい こんにちは パーソンナリティーの吉野康邦です
This is the one and only Yoshino Yasukuni, comin' at you live!
My guest today on the last day of the fair is the president of the Classics Club,
本日最終日のゲストは古典部の部長
Chitanda Eru from first year class A!
1年A組の千反田えるさんでーす
Thank you very much!
はい よろしくお願いします
状況は非科学的に 感情のモンタージュ
The situation is unscientific
A montage of emotions
誰が誰を呼んでる
Who's calling who?
振り向けば逃げてく視線（感じる）
You look away when our eyes are about to meet
I can feel it
気のせいじゃつれないよ アンテナは才能って言うでしょ
Am I just imagining things? It's so cold of you
It takes talent to read minds
だって（だって） 知りたい（君は違うの？）
You know
I wanna know
Don't you?
青春の温度差 今のうち正してあげるよ
I'll fix the fire of youth in your heart while I can
明日解決するなら 今でもよくない？
If we can do it today why leave it for tomorrow
君のミステリー解いてみたい
I want to solve your mystery
少年の秘密めいた背中探せ（今日も）
Look for the back of the boy, burdened with secrets
Even today
君はファンタジー 惹かれてゆくよ（ずるい）
You are a fantasy and I'm drawn to you
This growing curiosity
膨らんだ好奇心 とりたくはないのに
There's no twist in the story
気になるよ 興味深い どうして
I can't stop thinking about it
It's so interesting
But why?
Next time: Kudryavka's Order.
次回　クドリャフカの順番
Kudryavka's Order